<part id="lasem-overview">

<title>Overview</title>

<para>
	Lasem is a GObject based library for the rendering and edition of Mathml and
	SVG documents. It supports gobject-introspection,
	making it usable directly from Python (<ulink type="http"
		url="http://live.gnome.org/PyGI">PyGI</ulink>) , Javascript
	(<ulink type="http" url="http://live.gnome.org/Gjs/">Gjs</ulink> or
	<ulink type="http" url="http://live.gnome.org/Seed">Seed</ulink>) or
	<ulink type="http"
		url="http://live.gnome.org/Vala">Vala</ulink>.
</para>

<chapter id="lasem-building">
	<title>Building and debugging Lasem</title>

	<para>
	  Lasem is built using <ulink type="http" url="http://mesonbuild.com/">meson build system</ulink>. Release tarballs are
	  stored on <ulink type="http" url="https://github.com/LasemProject/lasem/releases">https://github.com/LasemProject/lasem/releases</ulink>.
	  You can build and install Lasem like <ulink type="http" url="http://mesonbuild.com/Quick-guide.html#compiling-a-meson-project">any other meson project</ulink>:
	  <literallayout>
	    <userinput>meson build</userinput>
	    <userinput>cd build</userinput>
	    <userinput>ninja</userinput>
	    <userinput>ninja install</userinput>
	  </literallayout>
	</para>

	<para>
	  The build can be configured at any time using <literal>meson configure</literal> in the build directory.
	    meson configure invoked without any other argument will show the configuration options.
	</para>

	<para>
	  On some platforms (like Ubuntu), you may have to configure the dynamic linker (ld) to let it know where the aravis
	  libraries are installed, and run ldconfig as root in order to update ld cache
	</para>

	<para>
		The LSM_DEBUG environment variable can be set to a colon
		separated list of debugging domains, which will make Lasem
		print out different types of debugging informations to the
		console. For example, the following command before running an
		Lasem based application will make Lasem print out DOM
		related informations:
		<literallayout>
			<userinput>export LSM_DEBUG=dom</userinput>
		</literallayout>
	</para>

</chapter>

<chapter id="lasem-fonts">
	<title>Required fonts</title>
	For the Mathml rendering, the following ttf fonts should be installed: cmr10, cmmi10, cmex10 and cmsy10.
	They are provided by the lyx-fonts package in fedora, and the ttf-lyx package in debian/ubuntu.
</chapter>

</part>
